A Guide to the Dina Stancheva Architectural Drawings, 1963-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Dina Stancheva Architectural Drawings, 1963-1990
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1997-017
1 box, 3 oversize; 10.4 cu. ft.
The Dina Stancheva collection consists of architectural drawings and photographs of designs Stancheva created from 1963 to 1990.
Dina Stancheva
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Dina Stancheva Architectural Drawings were donated to Special Collections in March 1997.
Biographical Information
Dina Nikolva Stancheva was born on November 18, 1925, in Nova-Zagora, Bulgaria, and raised in Sofia, Bulgaria. She was educated at the Sofia Art Academy, the Ecole Speciale d'Architecture and the Ecole des Beaux Arts in Paris, and at Sofia Polytechnic, where she received her architecture degree. She worked in the Sofia architectural organization Sofproekt from 1952 to 1972, when she became head of the design studio. She retired in 1982 but continued to work for Sofproekt for a few more years until she established a private practice. She closed her office in 1994.
Stancheva received the Koliu Ficheto award in 1968 for her design of a daycare center, the Red Banner of Labor award in 1977 for the Cultural Center in Pancharevo, and the gold badge of the Union of Bulgarian Architects in 1985 for her outstanding contributions to Bulgarian architecture, among other awards.
Scope and Content
The Dina Stancheva collection consists of architectural drawings and photographs of designs Stancheva created from 1963 to 1990. Many of the designs are of daycare centers and kindergartens in Sofia, Bulgaria.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- "Barwmov" School in "Zaimov" neighborhood, Sofia, 1956-1958. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Kindergarten in "Zapaden park" neighborhood, Sofia, 1962-1964. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Preliminary study for the Institute for Industrial Asthetic and Institute for Glass and Ceramic, Sofia, 1972. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Pedestrian passageway under "Bulgaria" and "Emil Markov" boulevards, Sofia, 1981. (Box-folder 1:4)
- Working drawings and blueprints for Vila for Dr. Alevsandur Todorov—Vilage Pancharevo, near Sofia, 1984. (Box-folder 1:5)
- unidentified bar, location unknown, n.d. (Box-folder 1:6)
- Biographical information and curriculum vitae of Stancheva, n.d. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Daycare center and kindergarten—"Krasno selo", Sofia, Bulgaria (9 drawings), 1963-1968. (Oversize 1)
- Preliminary drawings for hotel at the lake near Pancharevo, Sofia (21 drawings), 1967. (Oversize 1)
- Plans for hotel at the lake near Pancharevo, Sofia (6 drawings), 1969-1970. (Oversize 1)
- Plans for restaurant at the lake near Pancharevo, Sofia (7 drawings), 1969-1970. (Oversize 1)
- Daycare center and kindergarten—South–East region of Sofia (8 drawings), 1969-1970. (Oversize 1)
- Preliminary drawings for cultural center—Pancharevo, Sofia (9 drawings), 1970. (Oversize 1)
- Detail of stone facing for cultural center "Videlina"—Pancharevo, Sofia (24 drawings) 1971. (Oversize 1)
- Preliminary design alternative A for Sports complex for the Academy of Social Sciences and Social Administration to the Central Committee of the Bulgarian Communist Party-Gorna Bania (10 drawings), 1971. (Oversize 1)
- Preliminary design alternative B for Sports complex for the Academy of Social Sciences and Social Administration to the Central Committee of the Bulgarian Communist Party-Gorna Bania (7 drawings), 1971. (Oversize 2)
- Working drawings for cultural center—Pancharevo, Sofia (24 drawings), 1971-1975. (Oversize 2)
- Feasibility studies for Institute for Industrial Aesthetics and Institute for Glass and Ceramic Manufacture to the Committee for Science and Technology (10 drawings), 1972. (Oversize 2)
- Preliminary Project for Institute for Industrial Aesthetics and Institute for Glass and Ceramic Manufacture to the Committee for Science and Technology (16 drawings), 1974. (Oversize 2)
- Working drawings for cultural center "Videlina"—Pancharevo, Sofia (17 drawings), 1976. (Oversize 2)
- Expansion of the Library and stone facing details for cultural center "Videlina"—Pancharevo, Sofia, 1976. (Oversize 2)
- Details for the chess game club for the cultural center "Videlina"—Pancharevo, Sofia (4 drawings), 1977. (Oversize 3)
- Masterplan for sports complex "Gara Iskur"—Druzhba, Sofia (13 drawings), 1977. (Oversize 3)
- First alternative for daycare center for 366th neighborhood-Bukata, Sofia (12 drawings), 1977-1978. (Oversize 3)
- Second alternative for caycare center for 366th neighborhood-Bukata, Sofia (12 drawings), 1977-1978. (Oversize 3)
- Option I project development for Institute for Industrial Aesthetics and Institute for Glass and Ceramic Manufacture to the Committee for Science and Technology (16 drawings), 1979. (Oversize 3)
- Option II project development for Institute for Industrial Aesthetics and Institute for Glass and Ceramic Manufacture to the Committee for Science and Technology (10 drawings), 1979. (Oversize 3)
- Working drawings for Sports complex for the Academy of Social Sciences and Social Administration to the Central Committee of the Bulgarian Communist Party-Gorna Bania (14 drawings), 1979. (Oversize 3)
- Second option for daycare center and kindergarten—Boiana, Sofia (13 drawings), 1981. (Oversize 3)
- Pedestrian passageway No. 7 under Lyudmila Zhivkova blvd.—Mladost, Sofia (4 drawings), 1983. (Oversize 3)
- Remodeling and renovation of the coffee shop for cultural center "Videlina"—Pancharevo, Sofia (3 drawings), 1990. (Oversize 3)